

Rosario Sygal

Business Administration/ Customer Service

Address: Las Magnolias no. 7. Bayardo, Puerto Plata

Email: sygal89@gmail.com
Phone no.: 829-610-6569

Graduated in Business Administration with more than seven years of experience within the service industry. Excellent interpersonal communication skills in both English and Spanish. Very organized, deadline oriented and self-motivated professional. Have the ability to prioritize tasks effectively and focus on meeting and exceeding goals.

Academic Background

Bachelor of Business Administration. Pontificia Universidad Católica Madre y Maestra (PUCMM). Santiago, Dominican Republic. (2013).

Certificate in Financial Strategies. Pontificia Universidad Catolica Madre y Maestra (PUCMM). Santiago de los Caballeros, Dominican Republic. (2015)

Work Experience

Self-Employed. Puerto Plata, R.D.

Mar.2019 - Current

Agricultural Project

- Planning and development of Watermelon farm.
- Sale of Bran for animals. Budgeting and maintaining financial records.
- Marketing and sale of farming products.

AiroDigital. Joplin, MO. United States.

Sept.2018-Jan.2019

Project Manager

- Draft meeting agendas and meeting notes. Assign and schedule project tasks.
- Schedule & lead project meetings with team members and clients.
- Prepare and monitor project schedules and budgets.
- Manage project scope. Audit all project deliverables.
- Assess and evaluate project success.

Lifestyle Holidays Vacation Club. Puerto Plata. R.D.

January - August.2018

Project Manager / Quality Assurance

 Guide customer service staff into shifting to a better organized communication structure (chat).

- Reporting and adjusting flaws of the new customer service systems.
- Implementing a quality control for customer service agents to make sure that the department complies with professionalism and effectiveness.
- Monitor emails, phone calls, and chat sessions in order to provide individual feedback to each agent on a consistent basis.

BuyRailings. (Remoto). Brookfield, CT. Estados Unidos June – December.2017 Inside Sales / Customer Service

- Provide excellent service to existing and prospective customers.
- Answering calls and assist customers by orienting them about the products and materials as well as placing their orders.
- Review customer provided drawings/designs and provide detailed quotation to customers. Process Web orders.
- Handle communications through retail websites such as Amazon and Ebay. Assist Warehouse staff to ship orders by freight.
- Checking stock and ensuring the completion of the order processing.

Lifestyle Holidays Vacation Club. Puerto Plata, RD. January.2014 – June.2017 Claims and Dispute Resolution Officer

- Review and analyze relevant documentation in order to respond to several types of claims.
- Preparation of legal documents.
- Retention of members through negotiations.
- Reporting activity of cancellations and chargebacks to upper management and relevant departments.
- Overseeing the entire operational process of the company to help prevent potential loses to the company.

Arise Virtual Solutions, Inc. (Remote).

January - April, 2013

Technical Support / Customer Service (Turbo Tax)

- Provide support and assistance to customers to find appropriate tax forms.
- Providing guidance to use the Turbo Tax System.

United Nearshore Operations (UNO). Santiago, R.D.

Jan.2010-Nov.2011

Customer Service

- Provide timely response to customer needs.
- Retention of customers in the event of cancellation requests.

Skills

- Languages: Spanish (Native), English (Advanced, as native), German (basic).
- Technical Skills: Microsoft Office, basic networking and troubleshooting.
- Other: Basic Accounting (Dac Easy), Basic Statistics (SPSS), writing and editing articles, transcriptions and translations (English/Spanish)

References

Lorena Pascual. Arbitration Manager. Lifestytle Holidays Vacation Club. (809) 890-1482 lorena.pascual@lifestyleholidaysvc.com

Vella Ramos. General Manager Caribbean Marketing Services (829) 548-5204 vellaramos@gmail.com

Robin Rodríguez. Business VP Grupo Estrella (809) 796-1144 rrodriguez@estrella.com.do